<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources | Voice Deepfakes Research Project</title>
    <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Resources</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sobre el reglamento europeo de la inteligencia artificial</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/23-11-07-reglamento-europeo-ia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/23-11-07-reglamento-europeo-ia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;La secretaria de Estado de Digitalización: “El progreso tecnológico no puede llevarse por delante derechos fundamentales”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El pasado 7 de noviembre de 2023 se publicaba en &lt;em&gt;El País&lt;/em&gt; est: &lt;a href=&#34;https://elpais.com/tecnologia/2023-11-07/carme-artigas-el-progreso-tecnologico-no-puede-llevarse-por-delante-derechos-fundamentales.html/&#34;&gt;noticia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How deepfake is your voice? Understanding the linguistic foundations of deepfakes</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;div id=&#34;r-markdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can embed an R code chunk like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;summary(cars)
##      speed           dist       
##  Min.   : 4.0   Min.   :  2.00  
##  1st Qu.:12.0   1st Qu.: 26.00  
##  Median :15.0   Median : 36.00  
##  Mean   :15.4   Mean   : 42.98  
##  3rd Qu.:19.0   3rd Qu.: 56.00  
##  Max.   :25.0   Max.   :120.00
fit &amp;lt;- lm(dist ~ speed, data = cars)
fit
## 
## Call:
## lm(formula = dist ~ speed, data = cars)
## 
## Coefficients:
## (Intercept)        speed  
##     -17.579        3.932&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;including-plots&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Including Plots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also embed plots. See Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:pie&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;par(mar = c(0, 1, 0, 1))
pie(
  c(280, 60, 20),
  c(&amp;#39;Sky&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sunny side of pyramid&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Shady side of pyramid&amp;#39;),
  col = c(&amp;#39;#0292D8&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#F7EA39&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#C4B632&amp;#39;),
  init.angle = -50, border = NA
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:block;&#34; id=&#34;fig:pie&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://example.com/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/index.en_files/figure-html/pie-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A fancy pie chart.&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: A fancy pie chart.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of audio recording in Israel attack on Gaza</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/23-10-19-gaza-conflict/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/23-10-19-gaza-conflict/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Link to the newspaper article &lt;a href=&#34;https://today.lorientlejour.com/article/1353910/al-ahli-hospital-attack-flaws-in-the-israeli-version-of-events.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this piece of news published last 19 October on the newspaper &lt;em&gt;L&amp;rsquo;Orient today&lt;/em&gt;, there are two references to a potential fabrication of an audio recording which could be key evidence to prove that Israel attacked a hospital in Gaza and tried to pass it off as Palestinian authorship. First, there is a reference to the timestamp of the video. Second, we find a reference to the speaker&amp;rsquo;s linguistic and phonetic output, which did not look credible, according to two independent Arab journalists. Is this a case of voice disguise? recording tampering?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fragment from the original piece (our highlight)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later in the evening, Israel’s official account on X released a video aimed at corroborating the Israeli narrative, supposedly demonstrating an Islamic Jihad missile hitting Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the video, which has since been removed, &lt;strong&gt;because of its timestamp&lt;/strong&gt;. Several internet users noted that the video was filmed at 8 p.m., nearly an hour after the attack occurred.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, the Israeli army claimed to have “proof” of Islamic Jihad’s responsibility for the attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“According to our intelligence,” Hagari said during a press conference. “It was an Islamic Jihad rocket that had misfired.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evidence presented included a voice recording that Israel said it had intercepted, featuring two unidentified Hamas operatives discussing the explosion, with one asking, “Was it fired from our side?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes, it seems so,” replied the other operative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, the question was asked again, and the same response was provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Surely, it’s no coincidence that the rocket exploded by mistake over a hospital? &amp;quot; asked the first fighter. “It’s because they’re firing from the cemetery near the hospital,” replied the second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to two independent Arab journalists, who spoke to UK’s Channel 4 News the recording was a fabrication &lt;strong&gt;because of “the language, accent, dialect, syntax and tone, none of which is credible.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigadores de la Universidad de Granada desarrollan un asistente conversacional para desmentir bulos.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/23-07-24-proyecto-iveres/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/23-07-24-proyecto-iveres/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proyecto IVERES: “Identificación, Verificación y Respuesta. El estado democrático ante el reto de la desinformación interesada”.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El proyecto IVERES trabaja en la creación de una herramienta de inteligencia artificial que nos ayude a detectar informaciones falsas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es un proyecto financiado por el Ministerio de Ciencia e Innovación perteneciente a la convocatoria de 2021, Proyectos de I+D+I en líneas estratégicas, en colaboración público-privada, del programa estatal de I+D+I orientada a los retos de la sociedad en el marco del plan estatal de investigación científica y técnica y de innovación 2017-2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;El pasado 24 de julio de 2023 publicaban este artículo sobre las dificultades en la detección de audios falsos: &lt;a href=&#34;https://iveres.es/avances-en-la-deteccion-de-fake-audios/&#34;&gt;enlace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
